## CRISTIAN BASQUE

#### **SUMMARY**

I am a **Head of Design** and **Entrepreneur** from São Paulo with 20+ years of experience, **strong design background** and dozens of projects developed. I am responsible for **leading Design & Innovation Strategies** and **Digital Transformation** through practices such as **Human Centred Design** (HCD) and **UX**. I am currently working at Neotix Interactive agency, **leading the design team** to build projects for national and global clients, helping them to navigate through complexity and finding **creative solutions** to users problems.

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

# Neotix Interactive Agency Head of Design | April 2020 - Present

I am responsible for building, managing and developing a talented **Design** and **Research** team and also to establish a **Design & innovation** mindset in the company.

Manage the design team to achieve the company's goals through methods and processes, **facilitating** and **organizing** tasks and the team's agenda, ensuring **delivery consistency** across all products through Design System.

Acting in the intersection between the **business**, **design & technology**, running **Product Discovery** sessions and building strategies to understand users behaviour through user researches before building the product.

Spread the **design mindset** through the company, conduct user testing, research, and discovery process, market research, and share its results to stakeholders and related areas.

## INFOSYS CONSULTING

Principal | Lead Designer | April 2018 - April 2020

After Diagonal was acquired by Infosys, I had a shift in my career, when I assumed a role of **Principal | Lead Designer** and my duties include many challenges such as:

Running ideation workshops in the Infosys Innovation Lab through **Design Thinking methodologies** in order to explore new opportunities both internally and externally.

Lead projects focused on **Digital Transformation**, building a strong customer relationship and driving innovation in big enterprises.

I have delivered meaningful **user experience**, enhancing user satisfaction and improving the way the users interacts with the application.

#### **INFO**

krisbasque.com +55 11 97285 8804 me@krisbasque.com 44 y.o | Single

#### **SKILLS**

Interpersonal Skills
Comunication
Collaboration
Problem Solving
Leadership
Storytelling
Product Discovery
Design thinking
Design Strategy

## **TOOLS**

Figma
Sketch
Adobe XD
Ilustrator
Photoshop
Invision App
HTML 5
CSS 3
XCode

## **LANGUAGES**

English - Advanced Hungarian - Interm. Portuguese - Native Aid companies to co-create creative solutions based on **Human Centred Design**, solving complex challenges and assisting users to achieve their objectives with simple, intuitive and user-friendly solutions.

Defining **brand strategy**, helping clients to better fit their voice and target the right market, while also maintaining brand alignment across market standards.

I have worked on modern design and easy-to-use **user interfaces**, ensuring that visual communication meets the client's needs, always focusing on the user.

#### **DIAGONAL DEV**

Co-Founder | March 2013 - April 2018

I co-founded Diagonal with a friend. Diagonal was a development studio focused on designing it's own and third-party projects, pushing design, development and creativity to the highest possible level. My role in the company was very extensive, including duties such as **UI / UX design**, **project management** using **Agile methodologies**, **Facilitation Design** using both **Design Thinking** and **Design Sprint**, recruiting, **innovation strategies**, market research, user research and taking part in all major decisions of the company.

In Diagonal we focused on **Mobile Development** both **iOS & Android**, we built internal applications (internal use only) for big companies.

In April 2018, we were acquired by a large tech company which changed the focus of my career, bringing me many new challenges.

www.diagonaldev.com

#### AGENDA HELLO

Co-Founder | January 2015 - Present

Agenda Hello is a B2B solution focused on shortening the distance between school, teachers, parents and students. Hello was designed, built and validated from concept to conclusion by the Diagonal team. I was responsible for finding a suitable market fit and did the market and user research. Through the development process, we ran some **ideation workshops** to develop a product in order to solve a real communication problem in the schools. I led the team and had an active role as **stakeholder** and **product owner**, in addition to handling all the **UX & UI** of the application. It was very intense and I had to wear different hats during the development process.

www.agendahello.com

#### **EDUCATION & COURSES**

Graphic Design - Escola Panamericana de Arte Specialisation in Facilitation Design - Echos Lab Design Sprint - Mergo User Experience Product Discovery - How Bootcamps Design Thinking - SAP Leonardo | Peru